Honey 3: Dare to Dance is a music, drama, family
film directed by Bille Woodruff.
While attending college in Cape Town, Melea Martin feels constrained by the
school's strict policies, and decides to set out on her own.
Searching for a way to use her talents as a dancer and inspire the community around her, Melea
rents a failing theater in order to put on a Hip-Hop Romeo and Juliet performance.
But much like the Capulets and Montagues, conflicts between cast
members threaten to bring the whole performance to a halt...
Melea Martin, played by Cassie Ventura.
Erik Wildwood, played by Kenny Wormald.
Nadine, played by Dena Kaplan.
Laser, played by Bobby Lockwood.
Ishani Magona, played by Sibongile Mlambo.
DJ Zubair Khumalo, played by Sivuyile Ngesi.
Honey 3: Dare to Dance is a 2016 American dance film directed by Bille
Woodruff and starring Cassie Ventura and Kenny Wormald.
It is the third installment in the Honey film series.
The film was released on Netflix and DVD and Blu-ray on September 6, 2016.
Filming for Honey 3 took place in Cape Town, South Africa.
The story revolves around a dancer named Melea Martin (Cassie Ventura), who wants to put on a contemporary hip hop dance production of Romeo and Juliet to honor her mother, with
boyfriend Erik Wildwood (Kenny Wormald), but her dreams of presenting the play through her prestigious school are crushed when she's kicked out for failure to pay her tuition.
Searching for a way to use her talents and inspire the community around her, she rents a failing theater in order to
present the dance show, but conflicts between cast members threaten to bring the whole performance to a halt.
The film, which is the second sequel to 2003's Honey, has a tenuous link to its predecessors, with no recurring cast members, and the
only canonical reference to the original film is that the main character Melea comes from Honey Daniels' dance studio.
It was followed by another straight-to-video sequel
Honey: Rise Up and Dance (2018).
The tone is emotional.